Martin Cook

Email - mcookaai@gmail.com

Started university to study Applied Artificial Intelligence wanting to take the computer skills already acquired during my career and expand these to face future challenges. Previously worked as a procurement and supply chain professional continually striving to improve processes in the workplace. Extensive experience of analysing sales data to meet demands of budgets, changing trends and seasons, and deadlines. Keen to expand knowledge and experience within new areas. Committed to understanding all aspects of a business and leading by example.

KEY SKILLS

- Building and maintaining relationships with suppliers to ensure successful, long-standing partnerships.
- Strong negotiating skills used to continually secure beneficial deals for new and promotional lines.
- Identifying and establishing new ways of using electronic sale and stock systems (EPOS) to improve accuracy of
 ordering and quality and reliability of information that can be extracted.
- Line management of small warehouse team.
- Supervision and coaching of junior colleagues.
- Advanced Excel skills.
- Project management as lead organiser of several highly successful triathlons for adults and juniors.

CURRENT

University of Gloucestershire (2020 -)

Studying for BSc in Applied Artificial Intelligence

CAREER

Oxford Products (2018 to 2021)

Cycle Hard Parts Buyer (Feb 2018 – September 2021)

Responsible for the sourcing and replenishment to satisfy the need of the company's 750 wholesale and trade customers. Category Management of highest volume and highest turnover product ranges.

Achievements:

- Re-branded, simplified and launched new lock range products, packaging, and marketing for AW2021.
- Launched re-branded brake and cable ranges with minimal waste of existing packaging.
- Improved availability of inner tubes from 60% (Feb '18) to 95% (June '18) leading to annual doubling of sales from 2018-20.
- Introduced monitoring of back orders and uptake of promotions to measure improvement.

Outline of role

- Regular reordering of all cycle parts and accessories with the aim of improving order fulfilment.
- Select monthly promotional lines across Oxford and third party brands and oversee creation of e-shot.
- Re-source products to maintain quality, improve margin and increase choice of suppliers.
- Lead product development of parts to spring/summer and autumn/winter seasonal launches.
- Work with design team and suppliers to update packaging to the latest company and legislative guidelines.
- Identify and fill holes in the current range.
- Work with QC and stock control departments to ensure quality of replenishment orders and stock accuracy.

PCM Group (1999 – 2017)

The largest independent bicycle retailer in the UK, wholesaling and retailing bicycles, parts and accessories. These are sourced from across the world and sold directly to customers via the company's chain of retail shops, online, and to independent bicycle dealers.

Purchasing Manager - Parts and Accessories (P&A) (August 2012 – November 2017)

Overseeing a warehouse team and office admin team

Office Manager (2003 – 2012)

Assistant Office Manager (2001 – 2003)

Sales Administrator (1999 – 2001)

EDUCATION

The Greensward Academy Sixth Form (1995 - 1997)

A level: English Language, Psychology

Southend High School for Boys (1989 - 1995)

GCSE: English Language, English Literature, Maths, Double-award Science, French, Technology, Latin, History

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Interests

Competing in triathlons, running races and recreational cycling, making breads and pastries.